A Guide to the John Redd Hutcheson Papers, 1917-1962
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
John Redd Hutcheson Papers 1917-1962
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 2/9
13 Boxes, 12.0 cu. ft.
John R. Hutcheson graduated from Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute (VPI) with a B.S. in Agriculture in 1907 and a M.S. in 1909. He later received a PhD from Clemson College in 1937. Hutcheson was employed as a livestock specialist with the Virginia Agricultural Extension Service (1914-19) and as Director of Extension Service (1919-44). He served as the ninth president of VPI from 1945 to 1947 before becoming chancellor of VPI (1947-56). Hutcheson also served as president of the VPI Education Foundation from 1948 until his death in 1962. Papers consist of official and personal correspondence and records.
John Redd Hutcheson
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The John Redd Hutcheson Papers were donated to the University Archives.
Biographical Information
Born in Charlotte Courthouse, Virginia, on January 12, 1886, John Redd Hutcheson graduated from Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute (VPI) in 1907 with a Bachelor of Science degree in Agriculture and received a Master of Science degree in 1909, also from VPI. He later received a PhD in 1937 from Clemson College. In 1914, Hutcheson joined the Virginia Agricultural Extension Service of VPI as a livestock specialist, and subsequently became director of the Extension Service in 1919. In January 1945, Hutcheson was appointed executive assistant to VPI President Julian Burruss, but soon took on many of the president's duties when Burruss became ill. Hutcheson was elected Virginia Tech's ninth president in August 1945. In December 1946, he became ill and was granted sick leave, at which time Walter Newman took over the duties of president. Although Hutcheson recovered from his illness, he did not return to his position as president. Instead, Hutcheson was elected chancellor in August 1947 and Newman became VPI's tenth president. In 1956, Hutcheson retired as chancellor but continued to work as president of the VPI Educational Foundation until his death on January 23, 1962.
Scope and Content
The John Redd Hutcheson Papers consist of correspondence and records, from 1917 to 1962. This collection contains official records from Hutcheson's tenure as president of VPI and includes correspondence and reports from groups such as the State Board of Agriculture and Immigration, the American Association for the Advancement of Science, the Association of Governing Boards, the Association of Land-Grant Colleges, the Association of South Agricultural Workers, the Association of Virginia Colleges, the State Board of Education, the Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, the Tennessee Valley Authority, the American Veteran's Committee, the Farm Bureau Federation, the State Agricultural Commission, and VPI's Committee on Post-World War II Agricultural Policy. There are also materials dealing with the American Council on Education, including correspondence, telegrams, course outlines, and budgetary materials.
In addition, this collection also contains personal records on topics such as the management of Hutcheson's dairy farm, Edgemont; health, life, auto, and fire insurance; the deaths of Hutcheson's son and two brothers; various family members; desegregation of public schools in Virginia; Hutcheson's involvement with the Presbyterian church; and his illnesses. Also included is a bound volume of The Breeder's Gazette, containing handwritten notes on the front endpaper and on an inserted sheet.
Arrangement
The John R. Hutcheson Papers are arranged alphabetically by subject matter in the following series: Series 1 Presidential Papers, Series 2 Personal Papers.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional information regarding Edgemont Farm is located in Ms2003-022.
- Presidential Papers
  - A-Miscellaneous, 1945-46 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abbitt, J.R., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Abbitt, J.R., 1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Accelerated Progran Termination Committee, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Aeronautics, Statement of Income Taxes and Expenses, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Agricultural Adjustment Agency (AAA), 1942-45 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - AAA, 1945-46 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Agricultural Commission, Acceptances, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Agricultural Commission, Letter to Sub-Committee, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Agricultural Commission, Sub-Committee Reports, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Agricultural Commodity Groups, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Agricultural Conference Board, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Agricultural Policy Postwar, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Agricultural Policy Postwar, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 13a)
  - Agricultural Policy Postwar, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 13b)
  - Agricultural Statistics, 1945-46 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Agricultural Units 1, 2, and 3, 1945-46 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Agriculture Department, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Airplane Mechanics School, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Airport at Virginia Polytechnic Institute, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Allotments, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Almond, J.L., 1946 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Alwood, W.B., 1943-46 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - American Association of University Women, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - American Council of Education, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - American Council of Education, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 25a)
  - American Council of Education, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 25b)
  - American Plant Food Council, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - American Veterans Committee, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Anderson, Wilhelm, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Applications, 1944-46 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Architects, Consultant's Report, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Architects, Fees, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Architects and Engineers, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Art Commission, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Association of Governing Boards, 1925-46 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Association of Land-Grant Colleges, 1945-46 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Association of Military Colleges, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Association of Southern Agricultural Workers, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges, 1929-46 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Audio-Visual Programs, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Audits, 1946-47 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - B-Miscellaneous, 1945-46 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Babcock, H.E., 1945-46 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Barringer, J.M., 1945 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Barringer, J.M., 1946 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Battle, John S., 1946 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Begg, R.B., 1946 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Begg, R.B. and McGauhey, P.H., 1946 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Berkness, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Bonds for Dormitories, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Bonds for Veteran's Housing, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Bradford. J.H., 1945 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Bradford. J.H., 1946 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Brown, R.M., 1945 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Brown, R.M., 1946 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Bruce, David, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Buchanan, W.P., 1946 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Buck, J.L., 1945 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Budget, Biennial Matters, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Budget, Forms and Information, 1940-44 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Budget, Statements, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Budget, Working Allotments, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Building Committee, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Building Permits, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Burch, T.G., 1946 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Bureau of Entomology and Plant Quarantine, 1938-46 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Burruss, Julian, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Byrd, H.F., 1946 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - C-Miscellaneous, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - C-Miscellaneous, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 68a)
  - Cale, Frank, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Capital Outlay Appropriations, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Carneal, Johnson, and Wright, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Cassell, S.K., 1945 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Cassell, S.K., 1946 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Catalogue Matters, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Chesterfield Cannery, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Commandant, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Contracts, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Conversion Program for the Cotton South, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Cothern, L.I., 1945 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Cowgill, C.H., 1945 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Cowgill, C.H., 1946 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Cultural and Social Program, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Current Affairs Club, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Curriculum Revision Committee, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - D-Miscellaneous, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Dairy Fieldmen's Association, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Danville Textile Training School, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Darden, C.W., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - The Deans, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Deferments, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Derring, Paul, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Derring, Paul, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Dietrick, L.B., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Dietrick, L.B., 1946 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Dietrick, L.B., 1946 (Box 3, Folder 94a)
  - Dietrick, L.B., 1946 (Box 3, Folder 94b)
  - Drinkard, A.W., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Drinkard, A.W., 1946 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Dunlevey, D.B., 1946 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - E-Miscellaneous, 1945-46 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Educational Policies Commission, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Ellis, W.T., 1942 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Engineering, Science, and Management War Training and Vocational Training, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - F-Miscellaneous, 1945-46 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Faculty Letters, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Faculty List, 1943
  - Faculty Meetings, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Faculty Salaries, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Farm Bureau Federation, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Farrier, P.H., 1946 (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Five-Day Work Week, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Fogelman, J.B., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Fogelman, J.B., 1946 (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Forester Applications, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Future Farmers of America, 1939-42 (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - G-Miscellaneous, 1945-46 (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Glade Spring Farmer's Club, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Graduate Teaching Fellows, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Gross, Paul, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - Group Hospitalization, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - Guidance and Placement Applications, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - H-Miscellaneous, 1942-45 (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - H-Miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - Harrison, M.C., 1946 (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - Harrison, W.R., 1946 (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - Hart, Harris, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - Hart, Harris, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - Hatcher, T.W., 1946 (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - Holdaway, C.W., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - Holdaway, C.W., 1946 (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - Holden, R.J., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - Home Coming, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Home Economics, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - Horticulture, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - Hospitalization Plan, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - Housing Information, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - Howard, D.J., 1945 (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - Humanities in Teaching Curricula, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - Hunt, R.E., 1945 (Box 4, Folder 137)
  - Hunt, R.E., 1946 (Box 4, Folder 138)
  - Hutcheson, Henry, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 139)
  - Hutcheson, J.R., 1945 (Box 4, Folder 140)
  - Hutcheson, J.R., 1946 (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - Hutcheson, T.B., 1945 (Box 4, Folder 142)
  - Hutcheson, T.B., 1946 (Box 4, Folder 143)
  - I-Miscellaneous, 1945-46 (Box 4, Folder 144)
  - Insurance and Bonding, 1943-44 (Box 4, Folder 145)
  - J-Miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 146)
  - Jardine, James, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 147)
  - Johnston, J.A., 1945 (Box 4, Folder 148)
  - Johnston, J.A., 1946 (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - Joint Activities Committee, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 150)
  - Jones, J.B., 1946 (Box 4, Folder 151)
  - Josten Manufacturing Company, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 152)
  - K-Miscellaneous, 1945-46 (Box 4, Folder 153)
  - Knote, T.W., 1946 (Box 4, Folder 154)
  - L-Miscellaneous, 1945-46 (Box 4, Folder 155)
  - Lamb, Brockbrough, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 156)
  - Lancaster, Dabney, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 157)
  - Lancaster, Dabney, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 158)
  - Land Grant Fund, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 159)
  - Land Purchase, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 160)
  - Lauderback, Charles, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 161)
  - Love, H.M., 1946 (Box 4, Folder 162)
  - Lunsford, Charles and Son, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 163)
  - M-Miscellaneous, 1945-46 (Box 4, Folder 164)
  - Mc-Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 165)
  - McNeil, R.H., 1945 (Box 4, Folder 166)
  - McNeil, R.H., 1946 (Box 4, Folder 167)
  - Mall, War Memorial, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 168)
  - Maroon Mask Drama Club, 1945-46 (Box 4, Folder 169)
  - Meetings, General, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 170)
  - Memorial Service, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 171)
  - Memorial Service, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 171a)
  - Memorial Service, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 171b)
  - Michael, R.D., 1946 (Box 4, Folder 172)
  - Miles, C.P., 1945 (Box 4, Folder 173)
  - Miles, C.P., 1946 (Box 4, Folder 174)
  - Military, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 175)
  - Military Colleges, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 176)
  - Military Colleges, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 176a)
  - Miller, G.T., 1946 (Box 4, Folder 177)
  - Moore, Sam, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 178)
  - Mumford, T.W., 1946 (Box 4, Folder 179)
  - Mumford, T.W., 1946 (Box 4, Folder 179a)
  - N-Miscellaneous, 1945-46 (Box 4, Folder 180)
  - National Association of Deans and Advisors of Men, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 181)
  - National Collegiate Athletic Association, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 182)
  - National Education Association of the United States, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 183)
  - National Resources Planning Board, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 184)
  - National Youth Administration, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 185)
  - Naval ROTC, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 186)
  - Newman, W.S., 1946 (Box 5, Folder 187)
  - Norris, E.B., 1945 (Box 5, Folder 188)
  - Norris, E.B., 1946 (Box 5, Folder 189)
  - O-Miscellaneous, 1945-46 (Box 5, Folder 190)
  - Oak Ridge Research Program, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 191)
  - Orientation Program, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 192)
  - Ozlin, H.W., 1945 (Box 5, Folder 193)
  - P-Miscellaneous, 1945-46 (Box 5, Folder 194)
  - Patent Policy, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 195)
  - Physician Applications, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 196)
  - Placement Office, 1946-47 (Box 5, Folder 197)
  - Postwar Agricultural Policy, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 198)
  - Postwar Development Committee, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 199)
  - Postwar Employment Policy, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 200)
  - Postwar Needs, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 201)
  - Postwar Organization, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 202)
  - Postwar Planning, Academic Sciences, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 203)
  - Postwar Planning, Engineering, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 204)
  - President's Annual Report, 1945-46 (Box 5, Folder 205)
  - Project Works Administration, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 206)
  - Q-Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 207)
  - R-Miscellaneous, 1945-46 (Box 5, Folder 208)
  - Radford College, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 209)
  - Radford College, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 210)
  - Rasche, W.H., 1945 (Box 5, Folder 211)
  - Rasche, W.H., 1946 (Box 5, Folder 212)
  - Redd, H.B., 1945 (Box 5, Folder 213)
  - Redd, H.B., 1946 (Box 5, Folder 214)
  - Research Foundation, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 215)
  - Retirement Plan, College, 1938-46 (Box 5, Folder 216)
  - Retirement Plan, State, 1945-46 (Box 5, Folder 217)
  - Richardson, C.E., 1945 (Box 5, Folder 218)
  - Richmond Extension of VPI, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 219)
  - Royer, R.S., 1945 (Box 5, Folder 220)
  - S-Miscellaneous, 1945-46 (Box 5, Folder 221)
  - S-Miscellaneous, 1945-46 (Box 5, Folder 221a)
  - Sabbatical Leaves, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 222)
  - Saunders, Fred, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 223)
  - Shelton, Farrar, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 224)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 225)
  - Southern Colonels Orchestra, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 226)
  - Southern Conference, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 227)
  - Southern Planter Magazine, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 228)
  - Southern States Cooperative, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 229)
  - Southern States Cooperative, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 230)
  - Spiers, John, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 231)
  - Squires, John, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 232)
  - State Agricultural Commission, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 233)
  - State Agricultural Commission, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 234)
  - State Board of Argiculture and Immigration, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 235)
  - State Board of Education, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 236)
  - State Chamber of Commerce, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 237)
  - State Farm Labor Advisory Committee, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 238)
  - Student Affairs Director, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 239)
  - Student Finance Board, 1945-46 (Box 6, Folder 240)
  - Student Life Committee, 1942-46 (Box 6, Folder 241)
  - Surplus Property, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 242)
  - Swecker, Celia, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 243)
  - Swink, Harry, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 244)
  - T-Miscellaneous, 1945-46 (Box 6, Folder 245)
  - Tate, Mildred, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 246)
  - Tennessee Valley Authority, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 247)
  - Tennessee Valley Authority, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 248)
  - Tennessee Valley Authority, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 248a)
  - Tilghman, Tench, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 249)
  - Traffic Regulations, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 250)
  - Treasurer of Virginia, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 251)
  - Tuck, William, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 252)
  - Tuck, William, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 253)
  - Tyssowski, John, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 254)
  - U-Miscellaneous, 1945-46 (Box 6, Folder 255)
  - United States Office of Education, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 256)
  - V-Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 257)
  - Vacations, Holidays, and Office Hours, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 258)
  - Van Oot, B.H., 1945 (Box 6, Folder 259)
  - Verner, Lief, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 260)
  - Veterans Administration, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 261)
  - Veterans Club, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 262)
  - Veterans Housing, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 263)
  - Veterans Registrataion, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 264)
  - Veterans Training, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 265)
  - Veterinary Education, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 266)
  - Vice-President Applications, 1945-46 (Box 6, Folder 267)
  - Vilbrandt, F.C., 1945 (Box 6, Folder 268)
  - Vilbrandt, F.C., 1946 (Box 6, Folder 269)
  - Virginia Advisory Legislative Council, 1941-45 (Box 6, Folder 270)
  - Virginia Association of Colleges, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 271)
  - Virginia Education Commission, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 272)
  - Virginia State Planning Board, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 273)
  - Virginia Truck Experiment Station, 1944-45 (Box 6, Folder 274)
  - Virginia Truck Experiment Station, 1944-45 (Box 6, Folder 274a)
  - Virginia Truck Experiment Station, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 275)
  - Vocational Rehabilitation Training, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 276)
  - W-Miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 277)
  - W-Miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 278)
  - Walker Jr., W.D., 1946 (Box 7, Folder 279)
  - Wallace, M.E., 1946 (Box 7, Folder 280)
  - War Board, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 281)
  - War Department, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 282)
  - Wartime Commission of the Federal Security Agency, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 283)
  - Water Supply and Sewage Disposal Plant, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 284)
  - Watson, J.W., 1946 (Box 7, Folder 285)
  - Webb Jr., L.W., 1945 (Box 7, Folder 286)
  - White, H.V., 1946 (Box 7, Folder 287)
  - Whittemore, J.W., 1946 (Box 7, Folder 288)
  - Wiley and Wilson Company, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 289)
  - Williamson, H.H., 1945-46 (Box 7, Folder 290)
  - Wilson, I.D., 1945-46 (Box 7, Folder 291)
  - Wine, W.E., 1945 (Box 7, Folder 292)
  - Woodrum, C.A., 1945 (Box 7, Folder 293)
  - Worthington III, G.Y., 1946 (Box 7, Folder 294)
  - Y-Miscellaneous, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 295)
  - Young, H.N., 1945 (Box 7, Folder 296)
  - Young, H.N., 1946 (Box 7, Folder 297)
  - Younger, W.L., 1945-46 (Box 7, Folder 298)
- Personal Papers
  - A-Miscellaneous, 1959-62 (Box 7, Folder 299)
  - Alderman, E.H., 1947-50 (Box 7, Folder 300)
  - Almond Jr., J.L., 1958-59 (Box 7, Folder 301)
  - Alumni, Class of 1907, 1957-59 (Box 7, Folder 302)
  - Association for the Preservation of Virginia Antiquities, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 303)
  - Atlantic Life Insurance, 1939-61 (Box 7, Folder 304)
  - Atlantic Rural Exposition, 1945-47 (Box 7, Folder 305)
  - Awards, 1941-58 (Box 7, Folder 306)
  - B-Miscellaneous, 1919-61 (Box 7, Folder 307)
    - includes discussion of desgregation of public schools in Virginia
  - Baltimore Federal Savings and Loan Association, 1955-61 (Box 7, Folder 308)
  - Banks, 1950-59 (Box 7, Folder 309)
  - Barkesdale Deed, 1917-23 (Box 7, Folder 310)
  - Barkesdale, T.E., 1926-34 (Box 7, Folder 311)
  - Blue Cross Health Insurance, 1954-61 (Box 7, Folder 312)
  - Brucellosis, 1937-57 (Box 7, Folder 313)
  - C-Miscellaneous, 19438-62 (Box 7, Folder 314)
  - Camp Sea Gull, 1954-55 (Box 7, Folder 315)
  - Campbell, Mabel, 1924-49 (Box 7, Folder 316)
  - Catlett, Charles and Family, 1955-61 (Box 7, Folder 317)
  - Catlett, Robert, 1956-61 (Box 8, Folder 318)
  - Chatham Oil Company, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 319)
  - Christiansburg Fuel and Supply Company, 1958-61 (Box 8, Folder 320)
  - D-Miscellaneous, 1945-61 (Box 8, Folder 321)
    - includes discussion of desgregation of public schools in Virginia
  - Dairy Production Program, 1946-57 (Box 8, Folder 322)
  - Danville Dairy Products Company, 1934-61 (Box 8, Folder 323)
  - Danville Department of Health, 1955-60 (Box 8, Folder 324)
  - Danville Frozen Food Service, 1958-61 (Box 8, Folder 325)
  - Danville Milk Producers Association, 1952-60 (Box 8, Folder 326)
  - Danville Water, Gas, and Electric Department, 1956-61 (Box 8, Folder 327)
  - Division of Animal and Dairy Industries, 1957-59 (Box 8, Folder 328)
  - Douglas, L.E., 1952-58 (Box 8, Folder 329)
  - Draper Road Property, 1954-56 (Box 8, Folder 330)
  - Dundas Property, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 331)
  - Dunton Drive Property, 1950-53 (Box 8, Folder 332)
  - Duties as Chancellor, 1947-55 (Box 8, Folder 333)
  - E-Miscellaneous, 1935-61 (Box 8, Folder 334)
  - Edgemont Farm, 1951-59 (Box 8, Folder 335)
  - Edgemont Farm, 1960-61 (Box 8, Folder 336)
  - Elliot, William, 1926-57 (Box 8, Folder 337)
  - Employment Offers, 1918-34 (Box 8, Folder 338)
  - F-Miscellaneous, 1945-62 (Box 8, Folder 339)
  - Farmer, W.A., 1957-60 (Box 8, Folder 340)
  - Federal Insurance Contributions Act (FICA) Tax, 1956-62 (Box 8, Folder 341)
  - Federal Land Bank, 1918-45 (Box 8, Folder 342)
  - Flue-Cured Tobacco Cooperative, 1951-59 (Box 8, Folder 343)
  - Franklin Welding and Equipment Company, 1956-59 (Box 8, Folder 344)
  - Fred, E.B. and Family, 1925-60 (Box 8, Folder 345)
  - Fry, Jordan, and Wilson Insurance Company, 1951-57 (Box 8, Folder 346)
  - Fulton, W.P., 1954-59 (Box 8, Folder 347)
  - Furniture, 1947-51 (Box 8, Folder 348)
  - G-Miscellaneous, 1934-61 (Box 8, Folder 349)
  - Gasoline Tax Refunds, 1957-62 (Box 8, Folder 350)
  - Genealogy, 1948-51 (Box 8, Folder 351)
  - Gordon, H.H., 1927-60 (Box 8, Folder 352)
  - Grange, 1950-61 (Box 8, Folder 353)
  - Guernsey Cattle, 1953-60 (Box 8, Folder 354)
  - H-Miscellaneous, 1926-60 (Box 8, Folder 355)
  - Halifax County, Agriculture Extension Agent, 1923-59 (Box 8, Folder 356)
  - Halifax County, Agriculture Stabilization and Conservation Committee, 1950-57 (Box 8, Folder 357)
  - Halifax County, Agriculture Stabilization and Conservation Committee, 1958-60 (Box 8, Folder 358)
  - Halifax County, Agriculture Stabilization and Conservation Committee, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 359)
  - Halifax County, Selective Service Board, 1942-44 (Box 9, Folder 360)
  - Highway Department, 1933-57 (Box 9, Folder 361)
  - Hutcheson, C.M., 1925-53 (Box 9, Folder 362)